

AJAY YADAV

ARCHITECT - TECHNOLOGY
♥ NEW DELHI, INDIA
♥ 9599913701

• DETAILS •

New Delhi India 9599913701 ajayyadav.asm@gmail.com

> Date / Place of birth 1988-12-22 New Delhi

• SKILLS •

Node.js, React, D3js, Advanced Javascript

Python, Django

Ruby, ROR

Golang

Scala

Clojure

Java, C/C++

Amazon AWS

Dockers, K8s

Data Visualization and Analysis

Messaging Queues, Elastic Search,
Data Streaming

Terraform, Cloud Formation

Caching Strategies

LANGUAGES

English

Hindi

PROFILE

I have been working as a Software Engineer with 9 years of experience. During my professional journey I have worked on various Web Applications and Micro-services. I have been working with cloud platforms like AWS extensively. I have been working on different languages and technologies in parallel that evident my capabilities of openness to learn and putting that to practice. I have been involved in techno-functional roles for domains like Finance, Supply Chain, Healthcare, Research and Marketing.

With an objective of advancing my growth, learning and experiencing new challenges, I am putting my Resume for your consideration.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Architect - Technology at Virtusa System (INDIA) Private Limited, Gurgaon March 2021 — Present

- Provide technical leadership for team and technology selection and optimizations.
- Create POC's for technology benchmark.
- Hands on development with Python, Clojure and JavaScript.
- Hands on development with Nextjs UI.
- Gathering technical requirements, create sprint plans and release plans.
- Coordinate with various tech-leads and architects to optimize the ecosystem and achieve consistent communication between various applications.
- Hands on working on creating and executing migrations strategies.
- Hands on working on infrastructure cost optimization, while creating and implementing various caching strategies.

Sr. Engineering Manager at Leapus Technologies Pvt Ltd, New Delhi

February 2021 — March 2021

- Hands on working on various web projects, using technologies in Javascript ecosystem
- Developing, deploying and managing micro-services.
- Leading team of 15 Passionate developers.
- Gathering requirements from Product owners.
- Managing sprint plans and release plans.
- Acting as POC for various stakeholders for technical details and insights.
- Managing 3rd party vendors.

Sr. Software Engineer at Thinksys Software Private Limited, Noida

September 2019 — January 2021

- Creating POCs and MVPs, to demonstrate benchmark and comparisons this also includes, exploring new technologies and platforms for technology adaptation.
- Managing and mentoring team to onboard the project and transitions.
- Technology migrations and upgrades that includes migrating the project into other technology, offloading parts of applications to micro services, optimizing the architecture for scalability, data integrity and resilience.
- Worked in techno-functional roles which includes refining the requirements and translating the requirements into viable products, this also includes defining the requirements and ensuring the compliance, security and best practices.

- · Creating reusable libraries and boiler plates.
- Managing diversified teams across technologies and different time zones.

Team Lead at Smiling Star Private Limited (Buddy4Study), Noida

May 2019 — September 2019

- Working as full stack developer with technology that includes Advance JavaScript
- Working on technology like Nodejs, Reactjs and Nextjs
- · Building Apis and implementation of GraphQL
- · Team management.
- · Working on multiple projects simultaneously

Lead Technical Specialist at Wildnet Technologies Private Limited, Noida

February 2019 — May 2019

- Working on Frontend technologies including NodeJs, ReactJs, D3Js
- Creating Reusable Javascript Libraries
- · Multi-threading and Clustering with NodeJs
- Socket Programming for real time communications.
- · Creating Rest-full Api's and GraphQl
- · Working on data visualization

Team Lead at Natural Paradise India Private Limited, New Delhi

January 2015 — January 2019

Overview

- Managing and leading the Development Team including Web Development,
 Machine Learning and Analytics.
- Undertaking various Researches, Collecting Data and Preparing Reports.
- · Machine Learning Algorithm Development
- Application Development and Deployment, which included Websites, Tracking and monitoring tools, ERP Softwares, Rest API, GraphQL and Web-hooks.
- Various 3rd party API integrations.
- Data visualization and analysis

Application Developer at Target Integration Private Limited, Gurgaon

March 2012 — January 2015

Overview

- Website Development
- CRM and ERP Development
- Rest API and Web-hooks Development

EDUCATION

B.Tech in Computer Science, Maharshi Dayanand University

July 2005 — March 2009

MBA with Dual Specialization in Finance and Marketing, Apeejay School Of Management

August 2010 — March 2012

MS Finance, ICFAI

June 2012 — October 2014

■ REFERENCES

References available upon request